[
  { "id": 101, "front": "Sicilian Defense", "back": "1. e4 c5", "pgn": "1. e4 c5", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 1010, "front": "Sicilian Defense", "back": "1. e4 c5", "pgn": "1. e4 c5", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "black" },
  
  { "id": 102, "front": "French Defense", "back": "1. e4 e6", "pgn": "1. e4 e6", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 1020, "front": "French Defense", "back": "1. e4 e6", "pgn": "1. e4 e6", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "black" },
  
  { "id": 103, "front": "Caro-Kann Defense", "back": "1. e4 c6", "pgn": "1. e4 c6", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 1030, "front": "Caro-Kann Defense", "back": "1. e4 c6", "pgn": "1. e4 c6", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "black" },

  { "id": 104, "front": "Ruy Lopez", "back": "1. e4 e5 2. Nf3 Nc6 3. Bb5", "pgn": "1. e4 e5 2. Nf3 Nc6 3. Bb5", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 1040, "front": "Ruy Lopez", "back": "1. e4 e5 2. Nf3 Nc6 3. Bb5", "pgn": "1. e4 e5 2. Nf3 Nc6 3. Bb5", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "black" },

  { "id": 105, "front": "Italian Game", "back": "1. e4 e5 2. Nf3 Nc6 3. Bc4", "pgn": "1. e4 e5 2. Nf3 Nc6 3. Bc4", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 1050, "front": "Italian Game", "back": "1. e4 e5 2. Nf3 Nc6 3. Bc4", "pgn": "1. e4 e5 2. Nf3 Nc6 3. Bc4", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "black" },

  { "id": 106, "front": "Scandinavian Defense", "back": "1. e4 d5", "pgn": "1. e4 d5", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 1060, "front": "Scandinavian Defense", "back": "1. e4 d5", "pgn": "1. e4 d5", "tag": "e4", "orientation": "black" },

  { "id": 201, "front": "Queen's Gambit", "back": "1. d4 d5 2. c4", "pgn": "1. d4 d5 2. c4", "tag": "d4", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 2010, "front": "Queen's Gambit", "back": "1. d4 d5 2. c4", "pgn": "1. d4 d5 2. c4", "tag": "d4", "orientation": "black" },

  { "id": 202, "front": "London System", "back": "1. d4 d5 2. Bf4", "pgn": "1. d4 d5 2. Bf4", "tag": "d4", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 2020, "front": "London System", "back": "1. d4 d5 2. Bf4", "pgn": "1. d4 d5 2. Bf4", "tag": "d4", "orientation": "black" },

  { "id": 203, "front": "King's Indian Defense", "back": "1. d4 Nf6 2. c4 g6", "pgn": "1. d4 Nf6 2. c4 g6", "tag": "d4", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 2030, "front": "King's Indian Defense", "back": "1. d4 Nf6 2. c4 g6", "pgn": "1. d4 Nf6 2. c4 g6", "tag": "d4", "orientation": "black" },

  { "id": 301, "front": "English Opening", "back": "1. c4", "pgn": "1. c4", "tag": "flank", "orientation": "white" },
  { "id": 3010, "front": "English Opening", "back": "1. c4", "pgn": "1. c4", "tag": "flank", "orientation": "black" }
]
